Concert Band Competition
Hurry!
Gosh, I'm so nervous...
Kyoto Concert Band Competition
Kansai Concert Band Competition
Kyoto Preliminary
Here it comes!
Gold!
We got gold!
I'm going to go tell Asami.
She's so nervous, she's hiding in the washroom.
The following schools will compete in the Kansai Competition.
Gold...
We got dud gold, but still gold.
Kousaka-san?
You're happy enough to cry, huh?
Congratulations, we got gold.
I'm so upset...
I'm so upset, I could die.
Why are people happy, when we didn't even make it?
Weren't we shooting for the Nationals?
Did you really think we could make the Nationals?
Aren't you upset?
I'm upset!
I'm totally upset!
Why did I believe the rumor that my breasts would get bigger,
once I was in high school?
I'm off.
Take care.
When my high school life began,
that was the kind of thing
I was thinking about.
Entrance Ceremony
Although there weren't many people from my middle school here,
Baseball Club
Congratulations on
your admissions!
this school was the only one with the sailor-style uniforms I'd always liked,
and because, in a lot of ways,
I wanted a fresh start.
Attention, new students!
Welcome to Kitauji High School.
It's the concert band.
To celebrate your admittance...
They're hopeless.
They suck!
They don't play together.
They're off-pitch and out of rhythm.
But well, I guess they aren't trying for Nationals...
But they really sucked.
What sucked?
Huh?
You said, "They really sucked."
Did I say that out loud?
Wait...
Who are you?
Me?
Hazuki Katou!
I sit behind you. Nice to meet you.
I'm Kumiko Oumae.
Nice to meet you.
So, what-
Take your seats!
You're in high school now.
You shouldn't make noise in class.
I'm unimpressed.
Explain the length of your skirts.
Fix them now.
Sorry.
I'll be in charge of class 1-3.
My name is Michie Matsumoto.
Michie Matsumoto
First, I'll call the roll.
Yuudai Asai.
Here.
Yuki Ishikawa.
Hiroko Uchiyamada.
Here.
Yoko Eguchi.
Kumiko Oumae.
Here.
Hazuki Katou.
Ryokuki...
Kawashima?
Sorry, it's "Sapphire."
Written as "green" and "shining."
Sapphire Kawashima...
Sapphire, huh?
I'm sorry.
That sounds awesome.
I won't make that error again.
It's fine.
Kumiko, let's walk home together.
Huh? "Kumiko"?
Yeah, isn't that your name?
Yeah, it is.
Right?
I'm Hazuki!
You can call me "Katou."
Call me whatever.
Don't you walk home with anyone else?
No.
I decided I'm going to make new friends in high school
and do all kinds of new things.
I'm counting on you, Kumiko-chan!
Episode 1
Welcome to High School
So what sucked?
Let's just forget that.
Opal-chan!
No, it's something greener.
Hey...
Hey, isn't that Tuba-kun?
Huh?
It's so cute, Tuba-kun.
I love it.
- Could I touch-
- Hey, Opal-chan.
It's "Sapphire."
Oh, sorry. Sapphire-chan...
You like it?
Yes! It's so cute...
What is it?
It's a tuba mascot character.
Tuba?
It's a brass instrument.
A brass instrument?
Midori was in the concert band, on contrabass.
Contrabass?
Midori?
Midori is my name.
You know, the name "Sapphire" is kind of...
Sapphire
I'd appreciate if you'd call me "Midori."
And "contrabass" is the name of an instrument.
This huge thing!
It's like a freakish violin.
Have you seen one?
I've seen one.
You have?
I was in concert band, too.
Really?
Um...
Oh, Kumiko Oumae.
Call her "Kumiko."
I'm Hazuki. Nice to meet you.
Copy.
What about you?
What part did you play?
Oh, baritone.
I used to play euph.
Yeah, I can see that.
H-Huh? UFO?
Not "UFO." It's "euph."
It's called a euphonium.
It's a smaller one of these.
Yeah? That's really small.
Until now, I've been in the tennis club.
But with high school,
I might join the concert band.
No way.
I was about to go watch the concert band.
How about we all go together?
Welcome to the Concert Band
Whoa, crazy!
That's a trumpet, isn't it?
I like those.
They look awesome!
Look, Hazuki-chan. That's a euph.
Let's see.
Huh, UFOs are huge!
Jeez, you surprised me, Kumiko.
You said it was smaller than Tuba-kun...
Oh, sorry.
Sax is nice, too!
H-Hazuki-chan...
Ow.
Are you all right?
What's this?
Are you here to watch?
Then, come in.
Come on, join us!
Gosh,
she's pretty!
Now, this is our school band.
You're the first visitors.
In commemoration, I'll give you candy.
Thank you.
Huh?
Asuka...
Yes?
We agreed not to talk to the new students too much,
so we don't scare them, remember?
Huh?
They're already terrified.
Sorry, make yourselves at home.
Nice to meet you!
Come on, let's go.
Bronze Prize
Kitauji Prefectural High School
Bronze prize.
Hey, what's that square thing?
That's a tuner.
You tune against it.
Yeah?
Oh? Are you a beginner?
Yes.
I see!
Then I'll teach you the basics of brass.
Asuka...
Fine, fine.
A tuning B-flat, please.
Trombone, place your note.
Horn, you're off. Listen carefully.
Let's do it again.
You can use your tuner.
What?
They were a bit off.
Really?
Kousaka-san?
Excuse me.
Are you here to visit?
No, I'd like to join.
Really?
Welcome to the concert band!
Hurry, register her for the club!
Now?
Obviously.
What if she runs away?
She isn't a cat or anything.
Maybe we should get going.
Thank you!
That girl was pretty.
Do you know her?
Huh? Well, it's more like
I was with her in the middle school band.
Then you know her.
Not too well.
That's it, huh?
But the band here wasn't, uh...
...as good as I expected.
Really?
That's right...
They're probably aiming for a Prefectural silver.
Silver would be pretty good, wouldn't it?
If we wanted to go to the Kansai
Competition or to the Nationals,
we'd have to get gold in each competition.
And it can't be a dud gold.
It has to be a proper gold.
Dud what? What's dud gold mean?
School Band
All experience levels welcome!
Especially boys!
Band competitions have gold, silver, and bronze prizes.
Representatives are chosen from the gold-prize winners,
and the ones not chosen are called "dud golds."
Like Sapphire-chan said, if you want to move on to the next competition,
you can't have a dud gold...
Phys-Ed
Was that complicated?
Yeah.
Sorry.
But maybe if the three of us join, we can be their saviors.
It isn't that simple.
No?
I'll do it.
I love music.
Music speaks to people's hearts, all throughout the world.
I believe it's a powerful language.
The signal isn't changing, is it?
I forgot to press the button!
Come on, Sapphire-chan...
It's "Midori."
Tap
How about you, Kumiko?
How about it?
The band?
Me?
I'm...
I'm not sure.
My train's here.
I'm going this way.
Bye.
See you tomorrow.
Oh, I get it now.
When you said they sucked, you meant the band.
Why?
Kousaka-san was there...
She's really good.
I thought she'd be at Rakushu or Rikka or somewhere.
Damn it...
What?
Hey.
Oh, Shuichi.
Huh?
We've known each other since we were little. At least say hi.
We're in the same school.
You're tying your hair back?
I guess...
Oh yeah, I saw Reina Kousaka.
I didn't know.
Though, aren't you a bit slow?
You told me not to talk to you, so I'm not talking to you.
Huh?
In the third year of junior high, you said, "Quit talking to me, ugly."
Oh, that was because you asked me,
"Are you eating at my place tonight?" in front of others.
That's not right, and I don't really have time for this.
Hey.
Sorry, I'm going home.
Hey, what are you doing about clubs?
I haven't decided yet.
Not band?
What about you?
Me?
Well, it isn't like there's anything else I want to do.
Band, I guess...
Oh.
I'm...
I'm not joining.
Huh?
I was thinking of joining, but I decided not to.
Why?
Because.
Bye.
What the...
I'm home.
Oh, welcome home.
How was high school?
Hmm... Meh.
Your sister's home.
Yeah?
Help me fix dinner.
Okay.
Band, huh?
Did you really think we could make the Nationals?
I didn't mean that in a bad way.
I just kind of blurted out what I was thinking.
And I was sort of happy that we got gold...
Dud gold is still a gold-
What are you doing?
You even wore a ponytail.
You're trying too hard on your first day.
Shut up.
And don't open the door without asking.
Fine, fine.
Sorry.
Oh, yeah.
I said, "Don't open it"!
Are you quitting concert band?
Why?
Because you're at Kitauji.
Quitting, huh?
Euphonium Technique
Fun with the Euphonium
High School Entrance Exam Questions
Middle School Science Experiments
World of Ensembles
Middle School English Dictionary
Geographical Dictionary
Language Questions
Mathematics Questions
High School Entrance Exam Strategy
History Terminology
Music Terminology
Let me see!
Which is supposed to be better luck, sue-kichi or kichi?
I think it's sue-kichi.
From the top, dai-kichi, chu-kichi, shou-kichi, kichi,
han-kichi, sue-kichi, sue-shou-kichi.
So kichi is better.
Th-Thanks.
I see.
Now I feel like getting a fortune, too.
Ah, whoops.
Daikichiyama North Junior High
Prefectural Competition
Shoot.
Excuse me.
Sorry.
Sports festival?
Heaven and Hell, was it?
Actually, Orpheus in the Underworld.
It's a very nice piece.
Well, then.
Slide to Unlock
Daikichiyama North Junior High
Prefectural Competition
Not too heavy-Conductor
Keep staccato light
Daikichiyama North Junior High
Prefectural Competition
Kumiko Oumae
Are you eating?
No.
Tap
It isn't working...
Huh?
Where did you get that?
I bought it.
Bought it? You actually bought it?
Yeah, just this.
It's too early.
You haven't even chosen an instrument...
Huh?
How do you play it?
I used to play contrabass.
Teach me.
Um...
Your lips.
Make your lips vibrate, like this.
Try it.
Now try it with the mouthpiece.
Not bad.
It worked!
It worked, right?
Yeah.
It worked! I made a sound!
How did you do it?
I don't know!
Oh, Kumiko-chan...
Do you want to join the concert band with us?
Okay.
Really?
Yeah.
Yay.
And so, I joined the Kitauji
High School Concert Band.
And now, the next piece begins.
To Be Continued